
export const quizQuestions_5 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'How do you handle form inputs in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['Using the document.getElementById method', 'With a useState hook', 'By calling an external library', 'Form inputs are automatically handled by React'],
      correctAnswer: 'With a useState hook',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the significance of using arrow functions in React functional components?',
      choices: ['They have their own this context', 'They make the code more concise', 'Arrow functions are mandatory in React', 'They are faster than regular functions'],
      correctAnswer: 'They make the code more concise',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'Why is it recommended to avoid anonymous functions in JSX properties?',
      choices: ['They cause memory leaks', 'Each render will create a new function instance, potentially leading to performance issues', 'Anonymous functions are not supported in JSX', 'They have a different this context'],
      correctAnswer: 'Each render will create a new function instance, potentially leading to performance issues',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is a higher-order component (HOC) in React?',
      choices: ['A component that returns another component', 'A component that renders only higher-order functions', 'The top-level component in a React application', 'A stateful component'],
      correctAnswer: 'A component that returns another component',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How can you optimize performance for a list of items in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['By using the PureComponent', 'Using the useMemo hook', 'By always forcing the component to update', 'Performance optimization is not possible in functional components'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using the useMemo hook',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'In React, how can you avoid prop drilling?',
      choices: ['By using global variables', 'With the useReducer hook', 'Using React context', 'Prop drilling cannot be avoided'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using React context',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of React’s useRef hook in functional components?',
      choices: ['To persist values across renders without causing re-renders', 'To reference DOM elements', 'To store the previous state value', 'Both to persist values across renders without causing re-renders and to reference DOM elements'],
      correctAnswer: 'Both to persist values across renders without causing re-renders and to reference DOM elements',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How can you dynamically change CSS classes in a React functional component?',
      choices: ['By directly manipulating the DOM', 'Using the useState hook to toggle class names', 'CSS classes cannot be changed dynamically', 'With the useEffect hook'],
      correctAnswer: 'Using the useState hook to toggle class names',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'What is the primary function of the useState hook in React functional components?',
      choices: ['To create a local state', 'To update the component’s props', 'For global state management', 'To create a reference to a DOM element'],
      correctAnswer: 'To create a local state',
    },
    
    {
      question: 'How does React handle events in functional components differently from HTML?',
      choices: ['Events in React are not different from HTML', 'React uses synthetic events for cross-browser consistency', 'Events in React are handled at the document level', 'React does not handle events'],
      correctAnswer: 'React uses synthetic events for cross-browser consistency',
    },
    
  ],
}